The demonic case that shocked America.
The Conjuring: The Devil Made Me Do It is a horror, mystery,
thriller film directed by Michael Chaves.
Paranormal investigators Ed and Lorraine Warren encounter what would
become one of the most sensational cases from their files.
The fight for the soul of a young boy takes them beyond anything
they'd ever seen before, to mark the first time in U.S.
history that a murder suspect would claim demonic possession as a defense.
Lorraine Warren, played by Vera Farmiga.
Ed Warren, played by Patrick Wilson.
Judy Warren, played by Sterling Jerins.
Debbie Glatzel, played by Sarah Catherine Hook.
Arne Cheyne Johnson, played by Ruairí O'Connor.
David Glatzel, played by Julian Hilliard.
The Conjuring: The Devil Made Me Do It is a 2021 American supernatural horror film directed by Michael Chaves, with
a screenplay by David Leslie Johnson-McGoldrick from a story by Johnson-McGoldrick and James Wan.
The film is a sequel to The Conjuring (2013) and The Conjuring 2 (2016),
and the seventh installment in The Conjuring Universe.
Patrick Wilson and Vera Farmiga reprise their roles as paranormal investigators and authors Ed and Lorraine Warren,
with Ruairi O'Connor, Sarah Catherine Hook in her feature film debut, and Julian Hilliard also starring.
Wan and Peter Safran return to produce the film, which is based on the trial of Arne Cheyenne Johnson, a murder trial that took
place in 1981 Connecticut, in addition to The Devil in Connecticut, a book about the trial written by Gerald Brittle.
Initial development for a third Conjuring film began in 2016, though Wan stated that he would not be
directing another film in the series due to scheduling conflicts with other projects.
Safran confirmed that the next film would not be a haunted house film.
By June 2017, it was officially announced that a third installment was in
development, with David Leslie Johnson hired to write the screenplay.
Michael Chaves was announced as the film's director, after
previously directing The Curse of La Llorona (2019).
Filming took place in Georgia in mid-2019.
Originally slated for a September 2020 release, the film
was delayed due to the COVID-19 pandemic.
The Conjuring: The Devil Made Me Do It was released by Warner Bros.
Pictures and New Line Cinema in the United States on June 4, 2021, and also had a
simultaneous month-long release on the HBO Max streaming service.
The film grossed $206 million against a budget of $39
million and received mixed reviews from critics.
A sequel, The Conjuring: Last Rites, was released in September 2025.
The film explores themes of supernatural, exorcism,
connecticut, sequel, paranormal investigation.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and intense.